hey everybody cassie here with kinder
professional and i am so excited today
to share with you
our fringe 101.
we are going to walk you through all the
steps to make a perfect fringe for any
haircut first we're going to start with
a curtain fringe then we're gonna work
our way into a rounded face framing
fringe i'm gonna then take you into a
squared fringe and then we're gonna work
our way into a pc
fun fringe this is a way that we can
just really show you the basics of
creating the right fringe for the right
haircut first things first when i am
thinking about french i need to think
about the head shape most importantly i
want to know where that fringe
compartment lives and the best way to
determine that is to
take a look at where the highest point
of the head is when i want a really
strong fringe it's important that i am
working from that point because that's
where the hair will start to fall
forward right so i lay my comb directly
on top of the head just to see where
that high point is
many times when we're doing fringe we
find that sometimes we get finished and
we have like those one or two pieces
that just kind of fall over to the side
or if we cut too far past this point we
end up cutting into our hairline a
little bit and we're like why doesn't
this match
this
is the explanation for all that this one
point will help guide us through any
fringe compartment placement so now that
i've determined where the high point is
i'm going to draw a triangular line to
my the recession on either side so i'm
going to take
a look under here with my comb and just
find out where that spot lives i know
where my high point is i know where my
recession is i'm going to put a finger
there and then i'm going to draw a line
with my comb
to that compartment
creating a perfect triangle section
right here and then matching that again
on the opposite side
and now you can see that that's where
that hair is going to live now when they
put their heads down
you can see that none of this hair is
falling kind of over top of that right
if i cut too much into this this is
going to fall this way the hair is just
going to fall the way it's going to fall
you can't change the way that the head
is shaped i'm actually going to just
remove the rest of the hair out of the
way and this will be the section that i
pin away
so to make sure that i don't cut into it
now with a curtain fringe
what i'm taking into consideration here
is how i want it to lay with the curtain
fringe we want it to be a little shorter
in the middle and split apart and we
also want it to kind of fall back i
think of you know almost like the 70s
bang right where you have like a split
and it kind of feathers back and away
from the face now for that to happen the
best thing for us to do is to create
shorter hairs that will push the longer
hairs back and that will give you the
best control and the easiest for your
client to style in the end because if
you're cutting it to the way that
they're going to style it it's going to
make it much simpler for them when they
come back in to finish that shape so
first and foremost i'm going to find the
middle part and i'm gonna work one
section at a time
so
i think it's best to stand the opposite
corner of where you're gonna cut so
we're gonna cut this piece on this side
and we're gonna cut this piece on this
side so i might work in compartments so
that i am taking
not so much hair it's always going to
depend on how much hair your client has
first and foremost i want to gauge how
short i want the top to be
in most cases i want it to live just
kind of at the bridge or below the
bridge of the nose here so that will be
my first cut is kind of determining
where
i want that to live i'm going to take my
scissors
and i'm going to slide cut
that whole section
then i'm going to bring over and match
now you can already see look how the
hair is pushing
toward that direction
these shorter hairs are pushing out to
the longer hairs so for my next section
i'm going to cross over on the other
side match up my shortest point to the
shortest portion and then
point cut my way down the other side
to match
[Music]
now that we have that cut i'm going to
go in with my round brush just to show
you that completed shape i'm going to
bring my round brush down blowing down
this way and back
to give it the accentuated
sweep of that curtain fringe and then
same way on the opposite side bringing
it down
and rolling it back
so as you can see we're finished with
our curtain fringe what's great about
this is that you have those shorter
hairs
pushing the longer hairs back on both
sides so you're getting that nice sweep
this is great for a long layered haircut
and perfect to just blend in for
everybody she can switch apart and go
either direction with this it's not a
full commitment when it comes to fringe
so next we're going to work our way into
a soft face framing fringe this is
actually
what i'm wearing so this is a great one
trust me i know how to do it
so as you can see we have the same
fringe compartment as we did before and
now we're going to be working with a
face framing fringe so the idea of this
is that this is the type of fringe
that'll lay directly over the eyebrow
it's just going to frame that face
really nicely this is a great fringe for
a lot of people it's strong it's bold
but it matches your face very simply so
it gives you this beautiful soft angle
right over your eyebrow arch so the way
that i approach this is
i can do one of two things depending on
how thick the hair is i can just take
the whole thing this will be the easiest
fringe you ever learn i can take the
whole thing in one sweeping section and
just take it right into the bridge of
the nose and just cut it or if i have a
lot of hair i might take this to two
sections so i'm going to show it to you
in two separate sections so for this now
i'm combing it all forward and now
you're going to see me bring it all
pulled together to the middle of the
bridge of the nose and we're going to
cut just a simple straight line
[Music]
so you can see with this it just softly
frames the eye
right over top of the eye now there's a
couple different ways that we can detail
this and finish this
um for myself i even do the same thing i
did with the fringe before which is that
i do the round brush and pull it away
from my face but this you know is a
pretty simple straightforward fringe
this is kind of one of those you know
a client comes in and she wants french
this is almost where i go she wants a
full fringe because this is a great
easy wearable looks good on everybody
and cut specifically towards your face
so it gives you that beautiful soft
but bold fringe this is a really natural
looking fringe so what i'm going to do
for styling is i'm just going to blow
dry it simply where it lays and let it
lay naturally so you guys can see the
finished result so now you can see that
we have this completed fringe
compartment it's beautiful this is a
face framing fringe and it literally
lays just perfectly
judging by the bridge of her nose you're
just working into that natural lay the
way the hair is going to fall so it's a
beautiful fringe on a lot of people this
is a great look for clients who want
like a dramatic change without losing
all their length or you know changing a
lot all over but it really just changes
the whole dynamic of the face structure
now for the next fringe we're going to
do we're going to do a really extreme
squared fringe now what's cool about
this is it it's super edgy it's
definitely bold but it is uh something
that i think is really
clean and
for the right cut i love this for like a
squared bob this is a really cool type
of fringe now
easily enough to go from this to a more
squared fringe the thing is is because
it's so precision to me it's really
important that you take nice clean
sections every time i think of this as
like the bob of fringe so for this
type of fringe because it's so important
that we are creating
a nice clean line
taking smaller sections i'll probably go
three maybe even four sections to create
this look so as you can see i'm using
the closed scissors behind to pull the
hair away from the face so it's not
sticking
and i'm using zero tension but using the
comb as my guide
[Music]
[Applause]
so the reason i'm using my comb as my
guide as opposed to my fingers is
because i want this to lay super flat to
her head
if i was to
use my fingers
i'm going to create an elevation which
is going to give me a bit of a stack
and that means that anything that lays
over top of this is going to be a little
bit shorter so i'm going to have a
little bit of wispies in the underneath
so you can do that but what happens then
is you come back in and you see that you
have all these little hairs in the
bottom that you're going to have to fix
up
so you can see as i'm dropping each
section it's really important that i'm
not taking so much hair that i can't see
my guide underneath another point is
making sure that my scissors are staying
very square so i'm not beveling them
in either direction so with this kind of
fringe when i blow dry i like to either
use a denman
often times like a five row denman which
is a really small one which will give me
a lot of control or for example on
mannequin hair like hers i'm actually
going to use
a comb to blow dry and i'm going to just
push one direction and then the opposite
direction and then pushing in the
opposite back and forth to create a
really nice clean
straight blow dry so i do this even on
myself i don't have mannequin hair but i
do have a bit of a cowlick and so what's
nice about that is that it will help
control and make sure that lays
perfectly
as you can see we are finished with the
square fringe very similar to your face
framing except again the corners are
coming up so you're much more square
it's much more dramatic this is a great
shape that goes with a bob or you can
even use this on long hair um this is
actually i was saying to the guys behind
the scenes earlier this is actually the
same haircut or the same fringe shape
that i use when people ask for that you
know
really beautiful audrey hepburn shape as
well so you could even see like if we
part this to the side
you're gonna have that classic audrey
hepburn type fringe as well so now i'm
going to take this dramatic square
shaped fringe into something even more
dramatic which is a really pc kind of
90s fringe for this fringe i actually
like to use my razor
um
it's really simple this is a really fun
specific fringe i think of this as
um
me reliving my 90s dreams so this is
that really pc kind of punk rock type of
fringe it can be used with a lot of
things i love it as dramatic i love
having it as a pc fringe with a long cut
but this is something this trick you can
use when you're doing short haircuts you
can use this trick on
on really actually any length of fringe
so for this section
i'm just taking and splitting it in half
taking that top section out of the way
and it's too much me for me to work with
this entire section at once so i'm just
gonna split it into two
i'm gonna take my razor and i'm gonna
weave my razor in and out creating kind
of almost like a weaved section like you
would
for
a highlight
you can already see
all that really dramatic using it on
this side
same thing just weaving my razor in and
out and i'm just taking off
that back section i'm going to take my
top section that i pulled from the top
here
bringing it forward but i'm going to
leave it pulled out straight from the
head instead of dropping it down because
i'm just do the same thing here just
weaving my razor in and out
and taking
and then with this kind of blow-dry
really the more haphazard the better
it's really meant to be super piecy and
super deconstructed so i'm just going to
blow dry it with my fingers and give it
a lot of detailed texture other thing to
take into consideration is that we
actually went from a really really
incredibly straight fringe so if i want
to
break up this line i can go in now once
it's dry with my scissors and just point
cut out some of that line that i might
see and just soften that even further so
as you can see fringe is a great way to
elevate your look or change your shape
or change your look and it can be very
subtle or it can be super dramatic
anything from your curtain fringe to a
face frame to a really bold square to
this nice piecy funky fringe there's
something for everybody we hope you
loved this video
i had so much fun making it if you liked
it let us know in the comments below
also let us know what else you'd like to
see
we love hearing from you and we hope you
like subscribe and follow kinder
professional for more video tutorials
just like this
[Music]